Register of the Raymond Albert Wheeler papers, 1898-1977
Hoover Institution Archives
Raymond Albert Wheeler papers
1898-1977
78062
Hoover Institution Archives
46 manuscript boxes, 6 oversize boxes, 5 motion picture film reels, 6 sound tape reels, 26 envelopes, 2 album boxes (29.0 linear feet)
Correspondence, speeches and writings, reports, diaries, memoranda, maps, motion picture film, sound recordings, and photographs relating to military engineering; the Panama Canal; World War I; American military operations in the China-Burma-India Theater during World War II; construction of the Stilwell Road; the surrender of Japanese forces in Singapore, 1945; clearance and widening of the Suez Canal, 1956-1957; development of the Lower Mekong River Basin; and engineering projects involving the World Bank.
Wheeler, Raymond Albert, 1885-1974
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1978.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical Note
1885 July 31 Born, near Peoria, Illinois
1911 B.S., United States Military Academy, West Point, New York
1911-1912 Construction engineer, Isthmian Canal Commission, Canal Zone, Panama
1912 Married Olive May Keithley, Peoria, Illinois
1913 Graduated from Army School of Engineering, Washington, D.C.
1917-1919 Commanded the Regiment in the Aisne-Marne, the St. Mihiel, and the Meuse Argonne offensives, and the march into Germany with the Army of Occupation
1919 Served with the American Peace Commission in Italy
1920-1921 Engineer Instructor, the Infantry School, Camp Benning, Georgia
1922-1926 Assistant Engineer Commissioner, Washington, D.C.
1926 Elected honorary member, American Institute of Architects
1927 Graduated from Command and General Staff School, Fort Leavenworth, Kansas
1927-1930 Assistant Engineer of Maintenance, Panama Canal, Balboa Heights, Canal Zone
1935-1936 Chief Regional Engineer, Work Projects Administration, Chicago, Illinois
1936 United States Representative, International Navigation Congress, Brussels
1937 Graduated from Army War College, Washington, D.C.
1937-1940 Resident Member, Board of Engineers for Rivers and Harbors, Washington, D.C.
1940-1941 Engineer of Maintenance, the Panama Canal, Balboa Heights, Canal Zone
1941 Assistant Chief of Staff, War Department, Washington, D.C.
1941-1942 Member, United States military mission to Iran
1942-1943 Commanding General, Services of Supply, United States Army Forces, China-Burma-India Theater
1944 Principal Administrative Officer, Southeast Asia Command
1944-1945 Deputy Supreme Allied Commander and Chief Administrative Officer, Southeast Asia Command
1945 Commanding General, United States forces in India-Burma Theater
1945-1949 Chief of Engineers, United States Army, Washington, D.C.
1949 Retired from active service as Lieutenant General, Chief of Engineers, United States Army
1949-1964 Engineering Adviser, World Bank
1952-1960 Represented the World Bank in negotiations between India and Pakistan over the use of waters of the Indus River
1956-1957 Head, United Nations Suez Canal Clearance Operations
1957-1958 Chief, Mekong River Survey Mission, Asia
1958-? Represented the World Bank in discussions with the Suez Canal Authority to study the prospects for the growth of, and to advise on the plans for improving, traffic in the Suez Canal
1960-1963 Worked on behalf of the United Nations on the public works construction program and transport system in Congo
1960-1969 Chairman, International Advisory Board for the Mekong Coordination Committee, representing, among others, Cambodia, Laos, Thailand and Vietnam
1964-1971 Member, Columbia Board of Revenue, British Columbia Hydro and Power Authority, Vancouver
1974 February 8 Died, Washington, D.C.
Scope and Content of Collection
Correspondence, speeches and writings, reports, diaries, memoranda, maps, motion picture film, sound recordings, and photographs relating to military engineering; the Panama Canal; World War I; American military operations in the China-Burma-India Theater during World War II; construction of the Stilwell Road; the surrender of Japanese forces in Singapore, 1945; clearance and widening of the Suez Canal, 1956-1957; development of the Lower Mekong River Basin; and engineering projects involving the World Bank.
International Bank for Reconstruction and Development.; United States. Army--Officers.; United States. Army. Corps of Engineers.; Africa.; China.; Egypt.; Engineers.; Mekong Valley.; Military engineering.; Moving-pictures.; Panama Canal.; Panama.; Phonotapes.; Stilwell Road.; Suez Canal (Egypt); United States--Armed Forces.; Vietnam.; World War, 1914-1918.; World War, 1939-1945--Campaigns--Burma.; World War, 1939-1945--China.; World War, 1939-1945--Engineering and construction.; World War, 1939-1945.
- Biographical File, 1898-1975 (Boxes 1-8)
  Scope and Contents note
  Address books, appointment calendars, autograph books, awards, biographical notes, certificates, clippings, correspondence, diaries, family papers, financial records, funeral records, medical records, memoranda, notes, pamphlets, passports, press releases, printed matter, posters, proclamations, telegrams, travel documents, and writings about Raymond Wheeler, as well as records relating to his high school in Peoria, Illinois and his years at West Point, New York, arranged alphabetically by physical form. See also: Oversize Materials.
  - Address books (Box-folder 1: 1)
  - Appointment calendars (Box-folder 1: 2)
  - Autograph book (Box-folder 1: 3)
  - Awards
    Certificates, citations, clippings, communiques, correspondence, memoranda, messages, pamphlets, press releases, printed matter, telegrams, and miscellany.
    - Boy Scouts of America (Box-folder 1: 4)
    - Brazil (Box-folder 1: 5)
    - China (Box-folder 1: 6-9)
      Includes messages in Chinese.
    - Laos (Box-folder 1: 10-16)
    - Netherlands (Box-folder 1: 17-18)
    - Siam (Box-folder 1: 19-22)
    - The Beavers (Box-folder 1: 23-25)
    - The Moles Society (Box-folder 1: 26-29)
    - The Society of American Military Engineers (SAME)
      - Hoover Medal (Box-folder 2: 1-10)
      - Goethals Medal (Box-folder 2: 11-12)
    - United Kingdom (Box-folder 2: 13-21)
    - United States Army (Box-folder 2: 22-27)
  - Biography
    - General (Box-folder 2: 28)
    - Correspondence, 1971-1974 (Box-folder 2: 29-30)
    - Notes (Box-folder 2: 31-32)
  - Certificates (Box-folder 2: 33-34)
  - Clippings (Box-folder 2: 35-37)
  - Clippings (Box-folder 3: 1-5)
  - Diaries (Box-folder 3: 6)
  - Family papers
    - Olive Wheeler (Box-folder 4: 1)
    - Virginia M. Wheeler (Box-folder 4: 2)
  - Financial records (Box-folder 4: 3)
  - Funeral records
    - General (Box-folder 4: 4)
    - Cards of sympathy (Box-folder 4: 5-6)
    - Correspondence
      - Undated (Box-folder 4: 7)
      - 1974
        - February-March (Box-folder 4: 8-10)
        - April-June (Box-folder 5: 1-3)
        - August (Box-folder 5: 4)
        - December (Box-folder 5: 5)
      - 1975 January (Box-folder 5: 6)
    - Donations (Box-folder 5: 7)
    - Flower records (Box-folder 5: 8)
    - Printed matter (Box-folder 5: 9)
    - Telegrams (Box-folder 5: 10)
    - Telephone calls (Box-folder 5: 11)
    - Tributes (Box-folder 5: 12)
  - Medical records (Box-folder 5: 13)
  - Membership cards, certificates, and related correspondence (Box-folder 5: 14)
  - Memoranda (Box-folder 5: 15)
  - News broadcast (Box-folder 5: 16)
  - Newsletters (Box-folder 5: 17)
  - Notes (Box-folder 5: 18)
  - Pamphlets (Box-folder 5: 19)
  - Passports (Box-folder 5: 20)
  - Press releases (Box-folder 6: 1)
  - Printed matter (Box-folder 6: 2)
  - Posters (Box-folder 6: 3)
  - Proclamations (Box-folder 6: 4)
  - Scrapbooks
    - Farm Creek Flood Control Project, East Peoria, Illinois, 1947 September 27 (Box-folder 6: 5)
    - 100th Annual Engineer Dinner, 1967 May 5 (Box-folder 6: 6)
    - River Chindwin, 1945 (Box-folder 6: 7)
    - Testimonial dinner, 1946 April 23 (Box-folder 6: 8)
    - Trinity River Project, 1938 (Box-folder 6: 9)
  - Subject file
    - Peoria High School, Peoria, Illinois (Box-folder 6: 10)
    - United States Military Academy, West Point, New York
      - General (Box-folder 6: 11)
      - Appointment letter and grade point average (Box-folder 6: 12)
      - Brochures (Box-folder 6: 13)
      - Bulletins (Box-folder 6: 14)
      - Clippings (Box-folder 6: 15)
      - Correspondence
        - 1956-1965 (Box-folder 6: 16-19)
        - 1966-1974 (Box-folder 7: 1-8)
      - Financial records (Box-folder 7: 9)
      - Maps (Box-folder 7: 10)
      - Memoranda (Box-folder 7: 11)
      - Notes (Box-folder 7: 12)
      - Pamphlets (Box-folder 7: 13)
      - Printed matter (Box-folder 7: 14-16)
      - Reports (Box-folder 7: 17)
      - Schedule (Box-folder 7: 18)
      - Telegrams (Box-folder 7: 19)
      - Miscellany (Box-folder 7: 20)
  - Travel records
    - General (Box-folder 7: 21)
    - 1941-1946 (Box-folder 7: 22)
    - 1947-1957 (Box-folder 7: 23)
    - 1948 (Box-folder 7: 24)
      Visit to Alaska.
    - 1958-1964 (Box-folder 8: 1)
    - 1965-1973 (Box-folder 8: 2)
  - Telegrams (Box-folder 8: 3)
  - Writings about Raymond Wheeler
    - Articles (Box-folder 8: 4)
    - Poems (Box-folder 8: 5)
  - Miscellany (Box-folder 8: 6)
- Correspondence, 1918-1974 (Boxes 8-12)
  Letters arranged alphabetically by correspondent. Includes letters written by Virginia Wheeler and others.
  - Undated (Box-folder 8: 7)
  - Unidentified (Box-folder 8: 8)
  - General
    - 1943-1944 (Box-folder 8: 9)
    - 1951 (Box-folder 8: 10)
    - 1953 (Box-folder 8: 11)
    - 1956 (Box-folder 8: 12)
    - 1958 (Box-folder 8: 13)
    - 1959-1964 (Box-folder 8: 14-19)
  - Abdorabo, Mohamed Abdala, 1959 (Box-folder 8: 20)
  - Abd Rabuh, Muhammad Abd Allah, 1959 (Box-folder 8: 21)
    Includes two letters in Arabic, including one addressed to Virginia Wheeler.
  - Ackerman, Adolph J., 1959-1970 (Box-folder 8: 22)
  - Albrecht, F. M., 1958 (Box-folder 8: 23)
  - Alford, Thomas L., Sr., 1968 (Box-folder 8: 24)
  - Anders, Leslie, 1962-1965 (Box-folder 9: 1)
  - Andrews, Arthur, 1972 (Box-folder 9: 2)
  - Andruss, Malcolm P., 1965 (Box-folder 9: 3)
  - Arthur, Bill and Katherine, 1918-1974 (Box-folder 9: 4)
  - Atkinson, Guy F., 1956-1964 (Box-folder 9: 5)
  - Bahr, R. C., 1964 (Box-folder 9: 6)
  - Banks, Michael H., 1974 (Box-folder 9: 7)
  - Bannion, Howard, 1970 (Box-folder 9: 8)
  - Bechtel, Stephen D., 1958-1972 (Box-folder 9: 9)
  - Bengston, L., 1967 (Box-folder 9: 10)
  - Benson, James, 1962-1964 (Box-folder 9: 11)
  - Berenhauser, Carlos, Jr., 1963-1970 (Box-folder 9: 12)
  - Berger, Lillian F., 1963-1967 (Box-folder 9: 13)
    Includes a letter to Ben Binson.
  - Bishop, Max W., 1965-1966 (Box-folder 9: 14)
  - Bixby, H. O., 1970 (Box-folder 9: 15)
  - Black, Eugene R., 1966 (Box-folder 9: 16)
  - Blake, Norman P., 1967-1968 (Box-folder 9: 17)
  - Blazina, Tom, 1964 (Box-folder 9: 18)
  - Bonati, Ralph J., 1964 (Box-folder 9: 19)
  - Bonny, J. B., 1958 (Box-folder 9: 20)
  - Bourscheidt, Paul F., 1967 (Box-folder 9: 21)
  - Bowdish, Frank and Virginia, 1966 (Box-folder 9: 22)
  - Bowman, Waldo G., 1966 (Box-folder 9: 23)
  - Boyer, Lonnie MacArthur (Mrs. Arthur Irving), 1965 (Box-folder 9: 24)
  - Bradley, John H., 1973-1974 (Box-folder 9: 25)
  - Bradley University (T. W. Arsdale, Jr., Kalman Goldberg and A. G. Haussler), 1961 (Box-folder 9: 26)
  - Britton, William H., 1964-1969 (Box-folder 9: 27)
  - Brown, Earl I., II, 1965 (Box-folder 9: 28)
  - Bruns, May, 1944 (Box-folder 9: 29)
  - Buehler, John P., 1964 (Box-folder 9: 30)
  - Bunche, Ralph, 1971 (Box-folder 9: 31)
  - Burke, John G., 1960 (Box-folder 9: 32)
  - Byrnes, James F., 1945 (Box-folder 9: 33)
  - Caldwell, John T., 1962 (Box-folder 9: 34)
  - Campbell, David P., 1967-1968 (Box-folder 9: 35)
  - Cantwell, Robert C., Jr., Mrs., 1968 (Box-folder 9: 36)
  - Carroll, John E., 1966 (Box-folder 9: 37)
  - Casey, Hugh J., 1963-1965 (Box-folder 9: 38)
  - Chase, C. E., 1963-1964 (Box-folder 9: 39)
  - Clark, Allen F., Jr., 1969 (Box-folder 9: 40)
  - Clarke, Frederick J., 1965 (Box-folder 9: 41)
  - Clay, Lucius D., 1967 (Box-folder 9: 42)
  - Claybourn, John G., 1964-1968 (Box-folder 9: 43)
    Includes letters addressed to Meredith Wilson and Frank Verbrugge.
  - Coad, Laccy W., 1960 (Box-folder 9: 44)
  - Coffey, Matthew B., 1967 (Box-folder 9: 45)
  - Connors, Selena A., 1967-1968 (Box-folder 9: 46)
    Includes letters addressed to University of Delaware and University of Illinois.
  - Cook, Frank B., 1964 (Box-folder 9: 47)
  - Cordier, Andrew W., 1957 (Box-folder 9: 48)
  - Coughlin, Robert E., 1970 (Box-folder 9: 49)
  - Crimmins, A. Holmes, 1964 (Box-folder 9: 50)
  - Cromartie, Luther M., 1965 (Box-folder 9: 51)
  - Cromelin, Eric, 1966-1972 (Box-folder 9: 52)
  - Curtin, R. H., 1973 (Box-folder 9: 53)
  - Darling, H. Velpeau, 1963-1974 (Box-folder 9: 54)
  - Davis, Mildred and Vic, undated (Box-folder 9: 55)
  - Deal, D. Vernon, 1970 (Box-folder 9: 56)
  - Debrett's Peerage, 1961-1974 (Box-folder 9: 57)
  - Delaney, Albert L., 1965-1973 (Box-folder 9: 58)
  - Demuth, Richard H., 1966 (Box-folder 9: 59)
  - De Wilde, Camille, 1966 (Box-folder 9: 60)
  - Dirksen, Everett McKinley, 1963-1967 (Box-folder 9: 61)
  - Dixon, John W., 1964-1965 (Box-folder 9: 62)
  - Dogan, Charles, 1970 (Box-folder 9: 63)
  - Donaldson, Birdena E., 1970 (Box-folder 9: 64)
  - Duke, C. M., 1965 (Box-folder 9: 65)
    Includes a letter from G. A. England.
  - Easterling, William L., 1967 (Box-folder 10: 1)
  - Eaton, Herb, 1965 (Box-folder 10: 2)
  - Edgett, Thomas N., 1960 (Box-folder 10: 3)
  - Eickhoff, Andrew R., 1964 (Box-folder 10: 4)
  - Eisenhower, Dwight D., 1956 (Box-folder 10: 5)
  - El Deeb, Mohammed Tawfik, 1963 (Box-folder 10: 6)
  - El Serafi, 1970 (Box-folder 10: 7)
  - Elustondo, Mable Garcia, 1965 (Box-folder 10: 8)
  - England, G. A., 1966 (Box-folder 10: 9)
  - Ervin, Sam J., Jr., 1970 (Box-folder 10: 10)
  - Esser, T., 1965 (Box-folder 10: 11)
  - Esso Touring Service, 1966 (Box-folder 10: 12)
  - Evans, Geoffrey, 1966 (Box-folder 10: 13)
  - Falkner, Francis M., 1964 (Box-folder 10: 14)
  - Ferraz, Octavio Marcondes, 1966 (Box-folder 10: 15)
  - Flesher, Carl W., 1966 (Box-folder 10: 16)
  - Flexi-Versal Corporation (G. A. Arnold, Elinor M. Fell, John P. Kitselman and Leslie J. Redard), 1951-1959 (Box-folder 10: 17)
  - Fosque, J. D., 1962 (Box-folder 10: 18)
  - Fowler, Donald D., 1965 (Box-folder 10: 19)
  - Fox, Joseph C., 1965 (Box-folder 10: 20)
  - Frederick, Calvin J., 1968 (Box-folder 10: 21)
    Includes letter addressed to Virginia Wheeler.
  - Fuchs, Ralph F., 1964 (Box-folder 10: 22)
  - Garner, Robert L., 1973 (Box-folder 10: 23)
  - Galloway, G. E., 1960 (Box-folder 10: 24)
  - Gardner, G. H., 1968 (Box-folder 10: 25)
  - Garner, Robert L., 1966-1967 (Box-folder 10: 26)
  - Gilbert Associates, Inc., 1963-1965 (Box-folder 10: 27)
  - Gillette, George W., 1958-1971 (Box-folder 10: 28)
    Includes letters addressed to O. O. Allsbrook, Charles G. Holle, Joseph C. Mehaffey, and Henry C. Rowland, Jr.
  - Gilmour, Matthew P., 1966 (Box-folder 10: 29)
  - Goddard, Eric, 1969 (Box-folder 10: 30)
  - Gordon, King, 1963 (Box-folder 10: 31)
  - Gore, John M., 1973 (Box-folder 10: 32)
  - Graffman, J. Holger, 1963-1968 (Box-folder 10: 33)
  - Gregory, Jean, 1971-1973 (Box-folder 10: 34)
  - Grosvenor, Gilbert M., 1965 (Box-folder 10: 35)
  - Grove, Philip, 1958 (Box-folder 10: 36)
  - Groves, Leslie R., 1959 (Box-folder 10: 37)
  - Grystal, J. S., 1964 (Box-folder 10: 38)
  - Gulhati, N. D., 1964-1966 (Box-folder 10: 39)
  - Hall, Ralph S., 1960 (Box-folder 10: 40)
  - Hamza, Kamel, 1957 (Box-folder 10: 41)
  - Hannis, Henry, 1971 (Box-folder 10: 42)
  - Harrington, M. C. J., 1963 (Box-folder 10: 43)
  - Hassan, Ahmad, 1965 (Box-folder 10: 44)
  - Hassan, Parvez, 1963-1966 (Box-folder 10: 45)
  - Hatch, John, 1966 (Box-folder 10: 46)
  - Haug, Edgar, 1965 (Box-folder 10: 47)
    Includes letter addressed to August Konow.
  - Hederen, O., 1963 (Box-folder 10: 48)
  - Heinrichs, Louis M., 1971-1974 (Box-folder 10: 49)
  - Hibbs, Ben, 1944 (Box-folder 10: 50)
  - Hicks, W. E., 1943-1968 (Box-folder 10: 51)
  - Hinman, George, 1963 (Box-folder 10: 52)
  - Holocombe, W. H., 1966 (Box-folder 10: 53)
  - Howlett, Duncan, 1965 (Box-folder 10: 54)
  - Hubard, Bill, 1965 (Box-folder 10: 55)
  - Hunt, Geoffrey, 1963-1974 (Box-folder 10: 56)
  - Hunter, Howard A., 1943 (Box-folder 10: 57)
  - Huske, Jean (Mrs. W. O.), 1963 (Box-folder 10: 58)
  - Idris, Mohammed, 1966 (Box-folder 10: 59)
  - Itschner, E. C., 1963 (Box-folder 10: 60)
  - Johns, Dwight, 1966 (Box-folder 10: 61)
  - Johnson, Algot F., 1959-1960 (Box-folder 10: 62)
  - Johnson, Lyndon B., 1967 (Box-folder 10: 63)
    Letter written by Virginia Wheeler.
  - Jones, John M., III, 1945-1970 (Box-folder 10: 64)
  - Kambhu, Xujati, 1964 (Box-folder 10: 65)
  - Kamel, Mostafa, 1964-1967 (Box-folder 10: 66)
  - Karo, H. Arnold, 1964 (Box-folder 10: 67)
  - Katzin, Alfred, 1957-1963 (Box-folder 10: 68)
  - Kaufman, Nathan B., 1967 (Box-folder 10: 69)
  - Keating, Kenneth, 1960 (Box-folder 10: 70)
  - Kennedy, Donald D., 1966-1970 (Box-folder 10: 71)
  - Kentz, Alvin, 1967 (Box-folder 10: 72)
  - Khosla, A. N., 1964 (Box-folder 10: 73)
  - Kinney, G. P., 1966 (Box-folder 10: 74)
  - Kirmani, S. S., 1963 (Box-folder 10: 75)
  - Kirpich, Phillip Z., 1963 (Box-folder 11: 1)
    Letter addressed to Phillip A. Drinker.
  - Kirsch, Wolff M., 1969 (Box-folder 11: 2)
  - Klostermann, J. M. W., 1957 (Box-folder 11: 3)
  - Klotz, Harry, 1965-1972 (Box-folder 11: 4)
  - Knapp, J. Burke, 1957 (Box-folder 11: 5)
  - Kocour, Ruth, 1964 (Box-folder 11: 6)
  - Kohloss, Fabius Henry, 1948-1973 (Box-folder 11: 7)
  - Krisman, Michael J., 1972 (Box-folder 11: 8)
  - Kwoh, Theodore, 1963-1967 (Box-folder 11: 9)
  - Lane, Cherry, 1971 (Box-folder 11: 10)
  - Lang, Edmund, 1967 (Box-folder 11: 11)
  - Langelaar, Gerrit, 1966-1971 (Box-folder 11: 12)
  - Lansing, Sam, 1966-1968 (Box-folder 11: 13)
  - Larrick, J. Frederick, 1965 (Box-folder 11: 14)
  - Laylin, John G., 1965-1967 (Box-folder 11: 15)
  - Leber, W. P., 1960 (Box-folder 11: 16)
  - Lels, Murk, 1957 (Box-folder 11: 17)
  - Lennon, Alton, 1964 (Box-folder 11: 18)
    Includes a night letter from George W. Gillette.
  - Liggett, Tom, 1968 (Box-folder 11: 19)
  - Lipscomb, Willis G., 1966 (Box-folder 11: 20)
  - Lockwood, Benjamin C., Jr., 1972-1973 (Box-folder 11: 21)
  - Lockwood, Cherry L., 1972 (Box-folder 11: 22)
  - Loesing, Vernon T., 1972 (Box-folder 11: 23)
    Includes a letter addressed to A. Dodman.
  - Lowdon, J. W., 1967 (Box-folder 11: 24)
  - Luce, Clare Boothe, 1944 (Box-folder 11: 25)
  - Luttman-Johnson, J. D. M., 1963 (Box-folder 11: 26)
  - McConnell, Ben H., 1972 (Box-folder 11: 27)
  - MacDonald, Peter, 1963 (Box-folder 11: 28)
  - McElheny, John D., 1960 (Box-folder 11: 29)
  - McGrath, David J., 1966 (Box-folder 11: 30)
  - MacKichan, K. B., 1956 (Box-folder 11: 31)
  - MacMillan, R. H., 1969 (Box-folder 11: 32)
  - McShane, James E., 1963 (Box-folder 11: 33)
  - Madigan, Jack and Sybil, 1972 (Box-folder 11: 34)
  - Makaus, G., 1960 (Box-folder 11: 35)
  - Markle, Joseph, 1965-1969 (Box-folder 11: 36)
  - Marsh, A. Fletcher, 1963-1971 (Box-folder 11: 37)
    Includes letters written to James D. Bronson by Henry Bahr and to Raymond Wheeler by George L. Fairbairn.
  - Marquis Who's Who, 1966-1971 (Box-folder 11: 38)
  - Mason, Frank, 1966 (Box-folder 11: 39)
  - Matson, J. W., 1964 (Box-folder 11: 40)
  - Maxon, Glen W., 1944-1964 (Box-folder 11: 41)
    Includes letters addressed to Virginia Wheeler.
  - Meredith, William T., 1943-1972 (Box-folder 11: 42)
    Includes a letter to John Picco.
  - Messegee, Gordon H., 1965-1972 (Box-folder 11: 43)
  - Michler, Gordon H., 1969 (Box-folder 11: 44)
  - MICOPERI (G. Makaus and Ing. Buttazzoni), 1958-1960 (Box-folder 11: 45)
  - Middlebury College, 1966 (Box-folder 11: 46)
  - Middleton, Troy, 1972 (Box-folder 11: 47)
  - Morgan, Graham C., 1967 (Box-folder 11: 48)
  - Mountain, Barry F., 1965 (Box-folder 11: 49)
    Includes a letter addressed to Selig Taubenblatt.
  - Mountbatten of Burma, Louis Mountbatten, Earl, 1945-1972 (Box-folder 11: 50)
  - Mueenuddin?, G., 1958 (Box-folder 11: 51)
  - Mynatt, Richard E., 1960 (Box-folder 11: 52)
  - Nebolsine, Ross, 1965 (Box-folder 11: 53)
  - Neumiller, Louis B., 1960-1969 (Box-folder 11: 54)
  - Nichols, Harold F., 1971-1974 (Box-folder 11: 55)
  - Noce, Daniel, 1949 (Box-folder 11: 56)
  - North, Earl, Mrs., 1968-1970 (Box-folder 11: 57)
  - Olivier, Henry, 1963 (Box-folder 11: 58)
  - O'Malley, Thomas, 1963 (Box-folder 11: 59)
  - 101 Association, Inc. (Mickey Kaliff and J. M. Niemczyk), 1962-1963 (Box-folder 11: 60)
  - O'Neill, James J., 1960 (Box-folder 11: 61)
  - Osborn, M. P., Mrs., 1964 (Box-folder 11: 62)
  - Over, Don, 1960 (Box-folder 11: 63)
  - Painter, W. D., 1959 (Box-folder 11: 64)
  - Parsons, Ralph M., 1964-1972 (Box-folder 11: 65)
  - Peers, W. R., 1967 (Box-folder 11: 66)
  - Pepe, S. Ernest, 1963 (Box-folder 11: 67)
  - Person, J. L., 1965 (Box-folder 11: 68)
  - Piland, Julius Lynch, 1965 (Box-folder 11: 69)
  - Poole, T. W., 1966 (Box-folder 11: 70)
  - Poolers Shoe Store, 1969 (Box-folder 11: 71)
  - Prentis, Edmund A., 1966 (Box-folder 11: 72)
  - Price, Byron, 1972 (Box-folder 12: 1)
  - Proctor, Carlton S., 1963 (Box-folder 12: 2)
  - Ramada Inn (Carl J. Boyer and Peter Georges), 1968 (Box-folder 12: 3)
  - Rasey, Ray, 1959 (Box-folder 12: 4)
  - Razel, Paul, 1962 (Box-folder 12: 5)
  - Reynolds, Doyle C., 1963 (Box-folder 12: 6)
  - Ritchie, Ann, 1960 (Box-folder 12: 7)
  - Roberts, Harrison H., 1965 (Box-folder 12: 8)
  - Robinett, P. M., 1963 (Box-folder 12: 9)
  - Robinson, Erma S. (Mrs. L. E. Robinson), 1965-1966 (Box-folder 12: 10)
  - Rockwell, Alvin J., 1964 (Box-folder 12: 11)
  - Rodriguez, Filemon C., 1963 (Box-folder 12: 12)
  - Ruffin, Peter B., 1971 (Box-folder 12: 13)
  - Rusk, Dean, 1953 (Box-folder 12: 14)
  - St. Lawrence, Lee, 1968 (Box-folder 12: 15)
  - Saltzstein, Robert A., 1968 (Box-folder 12: 16)
  - Schaaf, Albert, 1965-1966 (Box-folder 12: 17)
  - Schaaf, C. Hart, 1965-1966 (Box-folder 12: 18)
  - Scharff, Maurice R., 1964-1965 (Box-folder 12: 19)
  - Schoon, Henry P., 1968 (Box-folder 12: 20)
  - Scholla, Paul F., 1962 (Box-folder 12: 21)
  - Scholtz, Herman F., 1966-1973 (Box-folder 12: 22)
  - Sciples, Carl M., 1964 (Box-folder 12: 23)
  - Seaman, P. C., Mrs., 1965 (Box-folder 12: 24)
  - Sells, Chas H., 1964 (Box-folder 12: 25)
    Includes Raymond Wheeler's correspondence with Herbert D. Vogel.
  - Sevareid, Eric, 1966 (Box-folder 12: 26)
  - Sherrill, Fred G., 1965 (Box-folder 12: 27)
  - Shields, James E., 1960 (Box-folder 12: 28)
  - Shiels, Archie W., 1964-1965 (Box-folder 12: 29)
  - Skerry, Harry A., 1968 (Box-folder 12: 30)
  - Slim, Bill, 1966 (Box-folder 12: 31)
  - Smith, Jacqueline, 1966 (Box-folder 12: 32)
  - Smith, Roderick, 1963 (Box-folder 12: 33)
  - Smith, Stephen E., 1965 (Box-folder 12: 34)
  - Smythe, James Frederick, 1972 (Box-folder 12: 35)